DAVID ROBB

103 – 1701 Kilborn Ave., Ottawa, ON CA K1H 6M8 · 1-613-260-9403 drobb2011@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-robb-42436a20/

Maintenance Manager

11+ years of experience supporting customer driven support to maintain and enhance the customer's Micro Focus software environment.

Through a dedicated offering, I work closely with the customer to ensure a stable and highly available environment 24x7. Proactively targeting weak points in the environment and offered guidance in improving service delivery. Documented all service requests and participated in generating monthly, quarterly and annual reports. Participated in contract renewals and new software purchases throughout the 9 years. Produced numerous documents to assist the customer in decision making for the planning and upgrade of their environment.

At the same time worked closely with backline engineering at Micro Focus and development to address product defects. Attended regular team meetings to discuss important topics, and quarterly all hands calls with senior management.

EXPERIENCE

JANUARY 2011 - PRESENT

SOLUTION SUPPORT ENGINEER, MICRO FOCUS SOFTWARE (CANADA) INC.

Dedicated to a single customer to support their environment where they utilize Micro Focus software including SUSE Linux, Open Enterprise Server, GroupWise email, ZENworks Management, Identity Manager, Application Lifecycle Management (ALM), Performance Center (PC), LoadRunner, Unified Functional Testing, and IDOL.

Working closely with customer staff to plan upgrades and rollouts of new products. Provide first level troubleshooting of configuration or performance issues with the above software. Engage second and third level engineering if necessary to resolve defects. Proactively help the customer to know what is coming and alert them to new threats and vulnerabilities.

Provide monthly, quarterly, and annual reports on activities and identify hotspots in the customer's environment that should be addressed.

Work closely with both the sales team and the support team to keep the customer engaged with our products so renewals go smoothly.

Customer – Royal Canadian Mounted Police (Shared Services Canada) – 2011 to present Customer – Canada Revenue Agency – June 2019 to April 2020

FEBRUARY 2005 - JANUARY 2011

SENIOR NETWORK ANALYST, BRUYERE CONTINUING CARE

Manage the day-to-day operation of the Bruyère network, which is a mix of Novell NetWare/OES and Windows Servers. Prepare written plans for the upgrade of systems, and produce proposals for changes to the network environment to enhance performance and stability. Assist with the backup of the network environment, and provide guidance on security issues within the network environment. Participate in project teams and meetings to ensure proper communications of changes are made to all employees.

Key Projects:

- Validated the current design of the AD environment at Bruyère and made recommendations for changes to the environment so that it could grow with Bruyère.
 Implemented the AD upgrade from Windows 2000 Server to Windows Server 2003.
- Planned and implemented the upgrade of Novell NetWare 5/eDir 8 to Novell NetWare
 6.5/eDir 8.7.x
- Planned, documented and implemented the GroupWise upgrade from version 6.5 to version 7.
- Lead technical resource for an internal IDM project connecting eDirectory, AD, GroupWise, and the Hospitals HR system.
- Initiated the Novell ZENworks migration from version 7 to version 10.
- Assisted with the development and testing of the disaster-recovery plan for the hospital.
- Planned and developed the scripts necessary to implement Novell SecureLogin in the hospitals network environment. However, the project was cancelled due to funding and lack of time.
- Planned the introduction of virtualization by initially introducing one VMware server to
 act as an IDM development platform. This has grown into a 4-node VMware cluster at
 one site, a two node cluster at a second site, and a stand-alone server at a third.
 Approximately 45% of the Bruyère environment has been virtualized to date.
- Planned and implemented a BlackBerry Enterprise Server for GroupWise to enable senior management to remain in touch with their e-mail and calendar from anywhere.
- Planned, tested, and implemented the migration from Novell NetWare 6.5 to Novell OES 2 (Linux) and eDirectory 8.8.5.
- Planned, tested, and implemented the Bruyère GroupWise system migration to OES 2
 Linux.
- Responsible for the creation of bash scripts to monitor and report on the health of SLES 10, eDirectory 8.8.5, and GroupWise
- Directly involved in the RFP process to procure a new storage system for the hospital. Drafted the RFP and selection criteria for the equipment. Dealt with vendor's questions and clarifications. After the selection and purchase were complete helped to implement and configure and migrate servers and services to the storage.
- Carried out a second Active Directory design validation in preparation for the upgrade to Windows Server 2008 r2 Active Directory.

NOVEMBER 1998 – FEBRUARY 2005

NETWORK CONSULTANT, INTEGRA NETWORKS CORPORATION

As part of the Integra team worked at various clients throughout the Ottawa area on both Novell and Microsoft networks helping to implement new technologies and services for our clients, and provide troubleshooting services. Assisted in the planning and documentation of work and the results from upgrades and new installs.

Key Projects:

- Microsoft Windows NT 4.0 workstation rollout at Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission.
- Microsoft Windows 95 workstation rollout at Royal Ottawa Hospital.
- Microsoft Windows NT 4.0 workstation rollout at Department of National Defense Judge Advocate General's office.
- Ongoing support of mixed Novell and Microsoft network at Advanced Business Interiors.
- Microsoft Windows 95 workstation rollout at SCO Health Service (now Bruyère Continuing Care).
- Upgrade of Novell NetWare 4.2 servers to NetWare 6 at SCO Health Service.

- Installation of a new NetWare 6 network along with GroupWise 5.5 and ZENworks 3.2 at Canadian Industrial Relations Board, along with a migration of users and data from NetWare 3.2.
- Ongoing support of a Novell NetWare network at Canadian Residents Matching Service.
- Support and upgrade of the Novell NetWare network at Ashbury College.
- Microsoft Windows XP workstation rollout at SCO Health Service.
- Upgrade of the ZENworks environment from version 3.2 to 7 at SCO Health Service.
- Microsoft Windows XP workstation rollout at Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission.
- GroupWise system administration at Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission.

EDUCATION

MAY 2007

BACHELORS OF PHILOSOPHY, UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN ONTARIO

Three-year program of philosophy and theology.

APRIL 1982

MARINE ENGINEERING PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE, CANADIAN COAST GUARD COLLEGE

Three-year program of engineering and sea duty training to become a marine engineer assigned to ships within the Canadian Coast Guard. Served in the Coast Guard fleet for 12 years and achieved the rank of Chief Engineer along with my First Class Marine Engineer certificate.

SKILLS

- Consistently working within a 15 minute SLA for the past 9 years
- Preparing presentations and analytics for regular customer meetings and giving the presentation to customer stake holders
- Excellent documentation skills

- Love of learning new products and tools
- In-depth knowledge of Linux and shell scripting
- Ability to listen to a problem, collect the necessary information for troubleshooting and arrive at a solution acceptable to the customer

ACTIVITIES

I love the outdoors, camping, hiking, kayaking, and sailing. With my West Highland white terrier, we go on daily walks regardless of the weather. I have lived all over Canada but have settled in Ottawa for the last twenty-three years. I am active on the Tenant's council for the buildings in my apartment complex and deal with issue tenants may be having with the property owner, or other tenants.

I have a passion for ships and the sea. I have sailed on the Pacific, Atlantic and Arctic Oceans, as well as all the Great Lakes. When I was with the Coast Guard, I spent four summers in Canadian Arctic waters. I am always up for a new challenge and love learning new things.

My list of professional certification is as follows

Novell 9770883

Certified Novell Administrator Certified Novell Engineer

SUSE

Certified Administrator in Enterprise Linux

Certified Engineer in Enterprise Linux

Microsoft 1053667

MCP +I MCSA

MCSA: Security

MCSE

MCSE: Security

MCTS – Windows Server 2008 / Vista MCITP – Enterprise Administrator

COMP001002001269

Security+ Linux+ Project+ ITIL

Foundations v2 00002777-01-2ZCK Practitioner: Change, Configuration, and Release 00005-8-01-31AN

Management v2